Clement Gendler

<u>clement.gendler@nyu.edu</u> • (914) 584-3238 <u>https://clementgendler.github.io/</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/clement-gendler/</u>

New York, NY

Data Scientist

Data scientist with experience in data analytics, marketing, and finance who strongly values creativity and enjoys finding unique solutions to any problem or challenge. Some passions of mine include but are not limited to coding, writing, working with data, and expanding my overall technical knowledge.

Skills

Technical: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Keras, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Git/GitHub, SQL, Spark, Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn, Tableau), HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Java, R **Additional:** Spanish speaker (professional working proficiency), Photoshop, Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint)

Professional Experience

General Assembly

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020 New York, NY

Data Science Fellow

- Completed 480-hour immersive course in python programming and data science
- Solved real-world problems by applying data collection, cleaning, visualization, analysis, modeling, as well as machine and deep learning techniques
- Analyzed and classified 5,000 Reddit posts using Natural Language Processing
- Collaborated with two Data Science Fellows to predict future COVID-19 hotspots
- Created a capstone utilizing LSTM and GRU neural networks to predict the outcome of a Chess game using only the moves played with 88% accuracy

Pink Sky, LLC

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019 Scarsdale, NY

Marketing Analyst Intern

- Analyzed qualitative research data for a mattress and personal care company via Excel
- Developed summary analysis for mattress research report, providing companies with insight into consumer choice and gaining an advantage over competing companies
- Designed a research presentation via PowerPoint, placing emphasis on visualizing summary analysis with a diverse variety of charts to illustrate findings

Gibbons Advisors

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019 White Plains, NY

Finance Intern

- Created cash flow projections of hospitals in bankruptcy via Excel
- Wrote analysis of June 2019 MedPAC report pinpointing areas of potential cost reduction

Weild & Co.

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 New York, NY

Summer Analyst

- Assisted in all areas of the company's services including strategic advisory and investor relations
- Tracked FINRA compliance and placement agent growth to promote business automation
- Analyzed, selected, and networked with over 500 FinTech funds to support raising capital
- Contributed to weekly executive team meetings, promoting intercompany collaboration

Education

New York University

- B.A. in Economics, Class of 2020, New York, NY, Buenos Aires Study Abroad August 2017 December 2017 General Assembly
 - Python Programming, Certificate of Completion, August 2019